

Senior Software Engineer seeking assignments in Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Gap Analysis, Python, Javascript, Core Java, Linux, XML, Ajax



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 10 Month(s)

Current Company: Ernst & Young Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Pune

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Gap Analysis, Python, Javascript, Core

Java, Linux, XML, Ajax, Android SDK

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Over 3 years of extensive experience in Web Development using Python, Node, Well conversant with Server management, Data Architecture, Data Analysis, Data Migration & Rest API.

Well Understanding in React and Node Architecture.

Hands on experience in deploying project inside Docker container.

Good understanding of D3.

In depth understanding/knowledge of Cassandra Architecture and various components such as Partitioning, Clustering, Batch, Table Index concepts to analyze large data sets efficiently.

Hands on Experience in Implementing Recommendation Engine using Statistical Model.

Knowledge of administrative tasks such as Creating and Managing Ec2 instance, Elastic Ip connection, VPC integration, Docker Container management and image creation.

Work Experience

Aug 2020 to Till Date

Ernst & Young as Senior Software Engineer

Provide service as per client requirement with the high level of output model

Quest Global as Senior Software Engineer

Jun 2019 to Aug 2020

Creating hierarchy structure by implementing Neo4j. Creating Rest API using node express and deployed inside docker infrastructure.

Responsibilities:

Created hierarchy product Tree structure

Addition of Node

Dynamic component creation using React

Creating Rest API using Node Express

Create Docker Image and upload to apple?s docker hub.

Deployed inside Kubernetes

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=dc8fddac08ed67265ee06e43c40028da5a5c0b514c1a0b14051040505d...

Tools/Technology/Platform

React Js, D3, Node.js, Neo4j, Docker

Duration: 3 Months

S&T Reporting Organization:

Quest-Global, BBSR

Client: Apple

The project consists of Reporting as well as monitoring, and performance management.

Responsibilities:

Created Script file to Automate procedures.

Worked on Migration and Consolidation activities between various clusters.

Worked on Version Up gradation task.

Support App Team by solving the various and different issues.

Worked on implementing and promoting Scripts.

Python , Cassandra Duration: 5 Months

Muvi as Full Stack Developer

Mar 2017 to Jun 2019

Recommendation Engine

This Project related to Collect data from various customer/domain and predict recommendation based on their history. It's a SaaS based platform.

Responsibilities:

Create Appropriate statistical Model based on various domain data.

Develop API gateway for seamless data transformation.

Connect Ui to backend using Ajax

Creating data model using Django-ORM.

Creating Authentication bridge between cross-server.

Used Pylint for testing.

Create Docker Image out of it.

Performed various performance tuning techniques to optimized performance.

Python, Django, S3 Duration: 2 Year

Android App Development

Developed Native Android applications. Applications used for Video, Audio streaming over CDN based URLs.

Responsibilities:

Worked all project phases: Planning, design, development, Testing, Install in Play Store.

Worked under Scrum and Kanban principle.

Understanding and Analysis of existing processes with respect to business requirements. Gathering new requirements,

Analysis, Design and Development.

Designing the approach for compatibility and customizing the application.

Connecting the App with the database using Rest API and Json Data as an intermediate.

Used Firebase for Real Time data Transfer.

Identify the issues and resolving. Collect statistics, monitoring execution plan.

Android APIs, Android SDK Tools, Core Java, XML, Firebase, Facebook API.

Duration: 5 Months

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Radhakrishna Institute Of Engineering And Technology Odisha in 2016

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Full Stack	

 $1/22/2021 \hspace{1.5cm} https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=dc8fddac08ed67265ee06e43c40028da5a5c0b514c1a0b14051040505d...$

Python, JavaScript	
macOS, UNIX, Linux	
Cassandra, Neo4j	
AWS, Django, Node.js, Docker	
React Js, D3 File System	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Odiya				

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time